



<u>josh-atwal.com</u>

josh.atwal@outlook.com

Josh Atwal

Data Scientist, Software Engineer

With a Master's degree and hands-on experience from an early-stage SaaS startup, I've cultivated a talent for quickly navigating unfamiliar landscapes. By combining research and execution I can hit the ground running and tackle any challenge I am given.

For example, my last role had me involved in: backend engineering and architecture, machine learning/data science, cloud infrastructure, database administration, LLM prompt engineering, digital content marketing, web scraping, and more.

In my spare time I frantically keep up with the latest in AI and consume many books/podcasts on technology, philosophy, and psychology. I also love hiking, play the drums, and am addicted to bouldering. Recently, I have been generating AI art and writing about it as a creative outlet.

Recent Experience

More thorough descriptions are available on the CV section of my website, as well as personal projects that I've worked on in my spare time. Topics include: text and image generative AI, facial emotion analysis, social media engagement, and more.

FOUNDING ENGINEER

Y CoffeeAl | 2021-2023

- Founding team (pre-seed) of a SaaS startup.
- Followed the company through the Y-Combinator accelerator program and multiple product pivots.
- Predominantly worked as a backend Python developer but other roles/responsibilities included data scientist, architect, prompt engineer, devops, cloud infrastructure, DB admin, and content marketer.
- Relied upon to independently solve difficult engineering problems. Worked as part of a development team and managed interns.

MASTERS STUDENT

Luma Analytics | 2021

- Using data to improve the analytics and insights available for amateur golfers, and uncover trends in the sport at large.
- Involved PCA, clustering, data visualisation, web scraping.
- Self-directed research with low-touch supervision.

COMPUTER VISION ENGINEER

Beca | 2020-21

- An end-to-end computer vision solution encompassing data labelling, model training, and prediction validation.
- Researched contemporary computer vision models before implementing Faster-RCNN and YOLOv5 in PyTorch, tuning them to the dataset, and comparing their performance.
- Acted as Product Owner and team leader, self-directing the project with minimal supervision.

Education

Masters in Data Science

- University of Auckland 2020-2021
- First Class Honours

Bachelor of Engineering / Bachelor of Science (conjoint)

- University of Auckland 2015-2019
- First Class Honours
- Final semester spent on exchange in Germany at the University of Freiburg

Technical Skills

- Data Science, Machine Learning, Statistics
- Generative AI, LLM prompt engineering
- Python, R, Flask, Pandas
- SQL and database administration
- Elasticsearch
- Kubernetes, Cloud infrastructure (GCP), Github Actions

References

Available upon request.